<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planning on Elastic Mint</title>
    <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/tags/planning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Planning on Elastic Mint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.elasticmint.com/tags/planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We need to talk about legacy software</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/08/29/we-need-to-talk-about-legacy-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/08/29/we-need-to-talk-about-legacy-software/</guid>
      <description>We Need to Talk about Legacy Software Sometimes we forget how much old software is out there. We talk about the software industry still being young and perhaps quite immature, but actually word processing software started reaching offices in the early 1970s - over 40 years ago. The first version of PowerPoint was released in 1987, public use of the internet began in 1989 and then exploded during the 1990s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are experienced software developers better?</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/08/12/are-experienced-software-developers-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/08/12/are-experienced-software-developers-better/</guid>
      <description>In short, it depends!
At Elastic Mint we take experience seriously. It’s one of the things that informs everything we do. We find that a good developer with a wealth of experience will make better decisions. They will reflect on things they have seen and done, learn from them, and then use that knowledge as and when appropriate.
Although it’s a bit old now, Peter Knego makes this point in his blog here, where he analyses reputation statistics on Stack Overflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using impact maps to improve product delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/03/30/using-impact-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/03/30/using-impact-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Like me haven&amp;rsquo;t you at times been frustrated by software that has been delivered late and not made the business impact you expected. A lot of time and money had been wasted due to assumptions being made with inadequate requirements; poor communication of team objectives and an overall lack of understanding, focus and misalignment with the overall business goals. As a developer I use interative delivery and this places emphasis on integrating learning from delivery and refining the scope and requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we think smaller teams are better</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/03/03/why-small-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/03/03/why-small-teams/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on lots of teams. Some good, and some not so. But what is it that makes a team successful?
There are the obvious things like the kind of people you have on the team. If the team members just don&amp;rsquo;t get on, if they don&amp;rsquo;t have the skills required to do the job, or they just aren&amp;rsquo;t interested in working hard then it&amp;rsquo;s clear the team will suffer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>