<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elastic Mint</title>
    <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Elastic Mint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:48:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.elasticmint.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Consequences of Achieving Business Objectives are too often Overlooked</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/09/21/consequences-of-achieving-business-objectives-overlooked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:48:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/09/21/consequences-of-achieving-business-objectives-overlooked/</guid>
      <description>If you are of a certain age you may be able to remember a time in the 1970s when predictions about the future of work and life were very upbeat. The view was that by 2020 we would all be enjoying much more leisure time and most people would have part-time jobs, working flexible hours. This future was painted as a kind of utopia that we should all aspire to and work towards achieving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Sweat the Small Stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/09/21/why-we-sweat-the-small-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:33:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/09/21/why-we-sweat-the-small-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard the phrase “Don’t sweat the small stuff”? It comes from a book by Richard Carlson called Don&amp;rsquo;t Sweat the Small Stuff and It&amp;rsquo;s All Small Stuff all about stopping little things in life driving you crazy.
In many areas of life this makes a lot of sense, however when it comes to writing code we’ve found that the “small stuff” really matters.
The problem is that after you have solved someone’s problems and written the code that does what they want, at some point there will be a new problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 10 Most Important Things Truly Gifted Software Developers Possess</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/08/14/things-gifted-developers-possess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 05:50:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/08/14/things-gifted-developers-possess/</guid>
      <description>The 10 Most Important Things Truly Gifted Software Developers Possess We have had the good fortune to work with some truly gifted software developers over the years. What is interesting is that the truly gifted developers are genuinely a breed apart. This led us to consider what it was about them that made them different from the rest of the field. None of the items in the picture above are the things we have in mind although it is possible that truly gifted developers may use some of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Certainty in Times of Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/07/05/increasing-certainty-in-times-of-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 08:12:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/07/05/increasing-certainty-in-times-of-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>Increasing certainty in times of uncertainty One of the lessons of the COVID 19 pandemic for businesses is that the degree of business uncertainty really can be much higher than even the most radical of scenario planners allowed for. Most disaster planning scenarios imagined the impact would be regional. Few, if any, accounted for a sustained, global impact on their business.
Of course, all businesses have to assume a degree of business certainty; otherwise businesses would never do anything or look beyond a quarterly horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/05/15/future-of-software-greater-digitisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 16:54:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2020/05/15/future-of-software-greater-digitisation/</guid>
      <description>The future of software development is driven by greater digitisation One thing we can be sure about when talking about the future of software development is that there will be a future. That said it will look very different from how it is today. According to IDC it took around 40 years to create the first 500 million apps but only 4 years to develop the next 500 million. Whilst predictions vary few question the inexorable rise of the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do We Still Need Orms?</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/11/02/do-we-still-need-orms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 09:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/11/02/do-we-still-need-orms/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember the first time you used an ORM (Object Relational Mapper)? For me it was something I wrote to make it easier to map data related to testing electronic devices into a SQL database. Different devices generated different test data, and so I used a convention to map the property names on the classes to the SQL tables and columns. At the time I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know what an ORM was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bespoke software</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/09/24/what-is-bespoke-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/09/24/what-is-bespoke-software/</guid>
      <description>What is bespoke software? Bespoke is just a fancy word for custom, right? Well, yes. And no.
According to putthison.com the word &amp;lsquo;originated in shoemaking, but gained in popularity through custom tailoring in England, where lengths of cloths were said to be “spoken for” or “bespoken” by another customer.&amp;rsquo; [1] ( https://putthison.com/the-overuse-of-the-word-bespoke-many-words-are/)There are several levels of custom-made clothes:
 Made-to-order - only the materials are customised Made-to-measure - the materials and the cut are tailored based on a single fitting Bespoke - garments are made through a series of fittings  Translating this into software development, we can think of &amp;lsquo;made-to-measure&amp;rsquo; as being like a fixed-scope, Waterfall development process, where we get the requirements up-front, build the software and then deliver it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curse of IoC and Why We Write Too Many Useless Tests</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/09/11/too-many-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 13:37:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/09/11/too-many-tests/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it seems that we simply go from one extreme to another. Once upon a time developers didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to write tests. Everything was tested manually. When changes were made the whole thing would need to be manually tested again. Sometimes we used test scripts, other times we just played around trying to break functionally. And then we couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember what we had done to break it!
Managers would roll their eyes in frustration when developers talked about writing unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We need to talk about legacy software</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/08/29/we-need-to-talk-about-legacy-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/08/29/we-need-to-talk-about-legacy-software/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we forget how much old software is out there. We talk about the software industry still being young and perhaps quite immature, but actually, word processing software started reaching offices in the early 1970s - over 40 years ago. The first version of PowerPoint was released in 1987, public use of the internet began in 1989 and then exploded during the 1990s.
Looking back it is striking how much has changed in a short period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are experienced software developers better?</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/08/12/are-experienced-software-developers-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/08/12/are-experienced-software-developers-better/</guid>
      <description>In short, it depends!
At Elastic Mint we take experience seriously. It’s one of the things that informs everything we do. We find that a good developer with a wealth of experience will make better decisions. They will reflect on things they have seen and done, learn from them, and then use that knowledge as and when appropriate.
Although it’s a bit old now, Peter Knego makes this point in his blog here, where he analyses reputation statistics on Stack Overflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>agile code (retreat on the beach)</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/04/19/agile-code-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/04/19/agile-code-retreat/</guid>
      <description>On 19th March Gordon and I attended a 2 day agile coding retreat in St Austell, Cornwall. Hosted by Kevlin Henney and Jon Jagger the retreat was organised for developers to discuss, practice and improve their software craftsmanship, communication and creativity. Having personally never attended such an event before I was interested to see if there was an opportunity for me to hone my programming skills to ultimately improve my performance as a developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Intermittent Test Failures With NCrunch</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/04/16/fixing-intermittent-test-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/04/16/fixing-intermittent-test-failures/</guid>
      <description>I was working with a company recently where we were using Xunit as our test framework, NSubstitute for mocks, stubs etc and we ran our tests using NCrunch whilst developing in Visual Studio. At one point during the project we noticed that some of our unit tests were failing intermittently. This is more common in longer running integration tests but not so common in unit tests. When we do see this behaviour in unit tests the cause is often shared state being accessed when unit tests are being run in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDD frameworks compared - SpecFlow and BDDfy</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/04/11/bdd-frameworks-compared/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/04/11/bdd-frameworks-compared/</guid>
      <description>I first learnt about writing unit tests following a project where we missed the deadline and spent far too long fixing and then refixing the code. I became frustrated that we would fix one thing and then something else would go wrong. When I saw how tools like NUnit and Rhino Mocks gave me the confidence to fix bugs and refactor it genuinely changed my working life. On my next project I determined to write tests as I went along and to be honest I&amp;rsquo;ve never looked back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using impact maps to improve product delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/03/30/using-impact-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/03/30/using-impact-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Like me haven&amp;rsquo;t you at times been frustrated by software that has been delivered late and not made the business impact you expected. A lot of time and money had been wasted due to assumptions being made with inadequate requirements; poor communication of team objectives and an overall lack of understanding, focus and misalignment with the overall business goals. As a developer I use interative delivery and this places emphasis on integrating learning from delivery and refining the scope and requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we think smaller teams are better</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/03/03/why-small-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/blog/2018/03/03/why-small-teams/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on lots of teams. Some good, and some not so. But what is it that makes a team successful?
There are the obvious things like the kind of people you have on the team. If the team members just don&amp;rsquo;t get on, if they don&amp;rsquo;t have the skills required to do the job, or they just aren&amp;rsquo;t interested in working hard then it&amp;rsquo;s clear the team will suffer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.Net</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/dotnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/dotnet/</guid>
      <description>blah blah blah</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Elastic Mint</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Process</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/agileprocess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/agileprocess/</guid>
      <description>blah blah blah</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Design</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/apidesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/apidesign/</guid>
      <description>blah blah blah</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Studies</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/casestudies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/casestudies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/contact/</guid>
      <description>blah blah blah</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Team Leadership / Management</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/services/distributedteamleadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/services/distributedteamleadership/</guid>
      <description>Distributed Team Leadership / ManagementIncreasingly companies have distributed teams of developers working in multiple locations. Sometimes these developers are allin the same country, and sometimes they are spread all around the world.Working with distributed teams is hard. Different time-zones, languages and cultures all conspire to make communication difficult,which can lead to problems like misunderstood requirements and lack of cohesion within teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>blah blah blah</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expertise</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/expertise/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/history/</guid>
      <description>blah blah blah</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Work</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/howwework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/howwework/</guid>
      <description>How we workEngageWe engage with our customers to properly understand the problem they are trying to solve.You would be forgiven for thinking that there is nothing particularly differentiating aboutthis. Any company worth its salt would seek to understand what the requirement is and in thiswe are no different.Where we differ from others is that we take a very flexible approach that allows for a certainamount of change in need and requirement along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Team</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/leadershipteam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/leadershipteam/</guid>
      <description>Andy Garner - PartnerAndy has been developing software professionally since 2001 starting off with Visual Basic and C++, and then continuing with C# and the various incarnations of ASP.Net. He has delivered software for companies both big and small including Just Eat, ASOS, Capita, Imperial Civil Engineering and the Cotswold Group.Having experienced both success and failure on projects, he believes passionately that getting the basics right is vital to delivering quality working software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Leadership Team</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/team/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Values</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/ourvalues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/about/ourvalues/</guid>
      <description>Our ValuesYou might recognise our values. When we came together as a partnership one of the first things wedid was to list all the things we would always do and all the things we would never do. For example,some of things that appeared in the &#39;always do&#39; list were to be open and transparent about what wedo, communicate both good and bad news, work collaboratively and deliver software we are proud of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Values</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/values/</guid>
      <description>You might recognise our values. When we came together as a partnership one of the first things we did was to list all the things we would always do and all the things we would never do. For example, some of things that appeared in the &amp;lsquo;always do&amp;rsquo; list were to be open and transparent about what we do, communicate both good and bad news, work collaboratively and deliver software we are proud of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/services/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/services/softwaredevelopment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/services/softwaredevelopment/</guid>
      <description>Software DevelopmentElastic Mint are a team of experts with many years experience in developing software.
We have worked on a wide variety of applications ranging from e-commerce sites written in ASP.Netdeployed to both AWS and Azure, to small web applications deployed on a single server.While we are happy to turn our hands to any technology, our main focus is on the Microsoft stacke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Consultancy</title>
      <link>https://www.elasticmint.com/services/technologyconsultancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elasticmint.com/services/technologyconsultancy/</guid>
      <description>Technology ConsultancyAt Elastic Mint we specialise in providing technology experts who can advise on technology choices based on many years of experience.This enables us to give reliable advice to senior management who need to make strategic decisions. It also enables us to joinexisting teams and give them guidance on how to get the most out of the technologies they are using, and the practices they needto follow to be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
